https://rodwoodman.com

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Front End Web UI | User-Focused | Dashboards

Versatile and thorough Web software developer motivated to engineer great solutions for end users. Balances systems-thinking with attention-to-detail to solve whole-product challenges with a high level of quality. Experienced at designing front-end dashboards and user interfaces as part of a collaborative team. Driven to improve scannability and demystify complexity for others. Highly skilled at getting apps that work both technically in code and subjectively within the expectations of the apps' human consumers.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, ExtJS, ReactJS, VueJS, Highcharts.
- Tools: REST APIs, VSC, Git, Bitbucket, vim, Sublime Text 2, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle.
- Methods: OOP, SPA, wikis, user-centered design (UCD), wireframes, card sorting, site maps.

#### **SAMPLE WEB APPS**

- <u>BoardGameinator</u>: Boardgame comparison site; ReactJS, Bootstrap, BoardGameGeek.com API; https://roderickwoodman.github.io/boardgameinator/.
- <u>TrailProfiler</u>: Charts and edits together GPX trail files and their associated JPG photo files; VueJS, ChartistJS, Bootstrap; <a href="https://roderickwoodman.github.io/trailprofiler/">https://roderickwoodman.github.io/trailprofiler/</a>.
- <u>ComparingStocks</u>: Tool for generating meaningful performance and allocation data for stock holdings; ReactJS, Alpha Vantage API; <a href="https://roderickwoodman.github.io/comparingstocks/">https://roderickwoodman.github.io/comparingstocks/</a>.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

ARUBA NETWORKS, Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

1800-person mobile-first networking company owned by Hewlett Packard Enterprise Company.

#### Senior Software Application Engineer - ClearPass

- Solely responsible for the ClearPass config sync tool that allows network admins to audit and optionally remediate the configurations of 100 clusters at once; the application is a Web front-end dashboard (ExtJS, SASS) and an Aruba-ClearPass-hosted backend (G0, REST APIs).
- Wireframed the UI design based on customer input.
- Created custom, internal APIs to connect the front end to the back end.
- Implemented back-end sorting, filtering, and exporting of audit results.

### Senior Software Application Engineer - Aruba Central Guest

- Jointly responsible for the cloud-native Guest product, a Web front-end dashboard (AngularJS, Bootstrap) for admins and cloud-hosted backend (Pyth0n, AWS); development follows a continuous integration model.
- Added troubleshooting features to the support dashboard to help the support staff diagnose errors.
- Connected to 3rd party APIs like Twilio and SendGrid.
- Exposed and demystified the entire ecosystem architecture by communicating with developers in multiple orgs and then diagramming and sharing it on the Confluence wiki.

#### TRUEPATH WIRELESS, San Jose, CA

2015 - 2016

11-person startup that provided terrestrial, wireless Internet to cruise ships near port.

## Senior Software Engineer - Network Management System

- Solely responsible for the Network Management System (NMS) product.
- Coded logs, displays, and reports all of the continuously collected network quality data from dozens of mobile endpoints; includes device-side "agent" code (PHP/bash/cron), Web front-end dashboard code (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, HighCharts, Google Maps), and server back-end code (Pth0n, Fl@sk, M0ngoDB, REST).

- Redesigned the dashboard UI to support multiple endpoint types and additional data streams. Gathered requirements from customer and business stakeholders.
- Sped up the pace of NMS improvements by releasing new code every 2-3 weeks.
- Collaborated with FW and network engineers to integrate new, third-party endpoint hardware
- Designed and implemented a compression algorithm that reduced the device-generated network quality stats files to 16% of their original size.

CISCO, San Jose, CA 2005 – 2014

#### **Diagnostic Software Engineer**

Catalyst 6000 and Nexus 6K (network switches)

HEWLETT-PACKARD, Cupertino, CA **Bring-up Engineer – Hardware & Software** 

2001 - 2005

NonStop Servers (fault tolerant compute)

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Engineering Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, CA

Bachelor of Science in Electronic Engineering California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING**

MEAN Stack Blackbelt - Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA
Web Design Certificate - UCSC Extension Silicon Valley, Santa Clara, CA

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

Photography. Writing. Editing. Deciding what matters most. Being a youth soccer referee.